MARISSA MERKT

Versatile writer and editor whose diversified experience has created a deep appreciation and understanding of the written word. Has successfully adapted written copy into the best form for the platform, from collaborating on brand social media strategy to captivating readers with hyper-local journalism.

EMPLOYMENT

The Brunswick Beacon, Staff Writer/Editor, Shallotte, NC

Mar. 2020 - Current

- Captivated readers with coverage of events and organizations in the area
- Informed the public of important government changes relevant to them in an easy-toread format
- Edited copy to ensure it abides AP guidelines, avoid grammatical errors and follow the newspaper's voice

EASTsideMagazine, Freelance Writer, Austin, TX

Aug. 2019 - Jan. 2020

- Feature Writer for Entertainment, Sip and Taste Sections; showcasing new restaurants and small businesses
- Focused on hyper-local journalism to bring locals a sense of connection across their communities

Cider Spoon Stories, Intern, Austin, TX

Feb. 2019 - May 2019

- Collaborated to develop brand strategy to effectively promote services provided in an engaging way
- Effectively copy-edited manuscripts for ghostwriting services and collaborated with head editor to deliver flawless products
- Successfully organized events to gain brand exposure

EDUCATION

Shippensburg University

Aug. 2013 - May 2017

B.A. Communications
Print and Public Relations emphasis
Sociology Minor

SKILLS

Copywriting and Copyediting, Social Media Marketing, Digital Journalism, Project Management, Organization, Time Management, Multitasking, Photography, InDesign, AP Style